（ヤサコ）新聞によると
According to the newspapers,
メガネをかけた子供の
交通事故が増えているそうです
there's an increasing rate of car accidents involving kids wearing glasses.
（ウチクネ）
おらおら 遅刻するぞ！
Hey, c'mon! You're gonna be late!
（ハラケン）おはよう フミエ
Morning, Fumie.
（フミエ）お… お… おはよう
G-Good morning!
ハラケンのペットが
まさかサッチーだったなんてね
I would never have imagined that Satchii was Haraken's pet.
（ヤサコ）人は見かけによらないわ
You really can't judge a book by its cover.
（フミエ）
こうして見ると どこにでもいる…
You wouldn't notice anything special just by looking at him.
普通のハラケンよね
He looks to be the same old Haraken.
あっ！　こ… こっち見たわ
H-H-He looked this way!
どどど… どうしよう
Wh-Wh-What should we do?
（ウチクネ）こら！
（２人）ハッ！
Hey!
他のクラスで何やっとるか！
What are you doing here? This isn't your class!
（ヤサコ･フミエ）
す… すみません！
S-Sorry!
（マイコ）はい 席に着いて
Everyone back to their seats!
でも サッチーって
Today's lesson is...
The Red Automaton
But isn't Satchii supposed to be Daikoku City's automaton?
大黒市(だいこくし)の
オートマトンなのよね
間違いないわ
ここに載ってるし
It is.
It's written here, too.
（ヤサコ）頭悪そうな文章ね
But it looks like it was written by an idiot.
（フミエ）“愛称 サッチー”
ってあたりが特にね
Especially the nickname he gave it... Satchii.
でも あの振る舞いは
I wouldn't call that silly behavior "cleaning up correctly".
キレイに掃除ってレベルじゃ
ないわよね
そうなのよ
Exactly!
メタバグ１個でも
ヒステリックに飛んでくるでしょ？
He goes nuts after every piece of metabug.
きっと導入したのはヒステリー女よ
I'm sure that whoever installed it was some hyster—
（マイコ）こら そこの２人！
（２人）ああっ…
Hey, you two!
大事な話してんだから
こっち見ろ！
I'm talking about a serious matter here! Pay attention!
最近 子供を狙った変質者が
出没しています
Recently,
some pervert targeting kids has appeared in this area.
もうすぐ夏休みですが
変な人に声をかけられない…
Summer break is about to start,
so be careful not to speak to strangers.
だああ～
っと… やあ！
Yo!
くれぐれも
変質者には気をつけるように
And be on the lookout for strange people; even more than you usually are.
（アイコ）悪の手先？
A pawn of evil?
ハラケンは
単なる根暗と見せかけて
Haraken only pretends to be naïve,
その正体は
悪の手先だったってわけよ
but in reality, he's a pawn of evil.
（アイコ）でも まさか
サッチーを飼っているなんて…
But it's hard to believe that his pet is Satchii...
見てないから
そんなこと言えんの！
You just say that because you didn't see it!
（アイコ）私 メガネとか
あまり興味ないからね
Well, I'm not really into glasses.
ハラケンって―
Why did Haraken start researching the Illegals in the first place?
なんでイリーガルの研究しようと
思ったのかしら？
うーん… なんでだろう？
Who knows?
あっ その研究ね
女の子に誘われてやったのよ
Oh, that's right!
It was a girl who asked him to do it.
でも その女の子が…
But that girl...
そうそう そうなのよ
Yeah, that's right, but...
何？
But what?
その子 死んじゃったのよ
その夏休み中に
That girl
died.
It happened over the summer break that year.
えっ 死んじゃった？
What? She died?
（フミエ）交通事故らしいわ
中津(なかつ)交差点の近く
Apparently, it was in a car accident
near the Nakatsu Crossroads.
（アイコ）私もビックリした
It scared me, too.
（フミエ）
だから イリーガルの研究は
So two people started the research,
２人で始めて
１人で仕上げたのよ
but only one finished it.
（アイコ）カンナって子よ
Her name was Kanna.
ハラケンは
近所で幼なじみだったのよね
They were neighbors and childhood friends.
（フミエ）でも あんまり
ショックな顔はしてなかった
But he never did show that he was shocked by the news.
いつもボーッとしてるし
Since then, he's always seemed to be in a daze.
そうかな？
Maybe you're right.
ハラケンって あんまり顔に
気持ちが出ないタチだから
Haraken isn't the type who'd let his feelings show.
ホントは
すごいショックだったかもよ
Maybe it was a huge shock to him.
それは それとしても
悪の手先ってことに変わりはないわ
Regardless of that,
it doesn't change the fact that he's an evil pawn.
ヤサコ 予定どおり
昼休みに決行するわよ
Yasako,
we'll act according to the plan at lunch time!
（ヤサコ）やっぱりやるの？
気が進まないな
You're really going through with it?
I'm not so sure...
（ハラケン）どこ？
なんで こんな所に呼び出すの？
Where are you?
And why did you call me here?
（フミエ）動くな！
（ハラケン）うわっ…
Don't move!
手を上げなさい！
おかしなマネをしたら撃つわよ
Hands up!
Try anything funny,
and I'll shoot!
（ヤサコ）えーっと…
あなたとサッチーの関係は何？
Um...
H-How are you connected to Satchii?
（フミエ）教えなさい！
（ハラケン）や… やめてよ
Tell us!
C-Cut it out...
ネタは すっかり挙がってんのよ
吐きなさい！
We're on to you!
Now confess!
わあっ…
I-I can...
You can?
守秘義務があって
しゃべれないんだ！
I can't reveal this secret because I have a duty of confidentiality!
（ヤサコ）守秘… あったわ
A duty of...
Here it is!
“守秘義務 職業上 秘密を―”
"Duty of Confidentiality"
The obligation to respect a client's affairs and not disclose information without due authorization.
“他に漏らしてはならないという
義務のこと”
なんかよく分からないわね
I don't understand this very well.
ハラケンは昔から
訳 分かんないわ
To be honest, I never understood Haraken at all.
でも 最初に会った頃は
もうちょっと明るい子だった
But he was a little less gloomy the first time we met.
フミエちゃんは ハラケンのこと
いつから知ってるの？
Fumie, how long have you known Haraken?
（フミエ）そうねえ
ちゃんと知ったのは やっぱり―
Let me see...
We first met last year because of his research on Illegals.
去年のイリーガル研究のときね
うちのクラブには…
いつからいたんだっけ？
I don't really remember...
when he joined our club.
（ヤサコ）家族とかは？
What about his family?
お父さんがペット会社の人ってのは
聞いたことあるけど
Well, his father works at a pet manufacturing company.
もともと無口でしょ？
But Haraken's not very talkative, you know?
あんまり自分のこと
しゃべんないのよね
He doesn't talk about himself much.
あっ 出てきたわ
Ah!
There he is.
あ～ ヤな感じ
What a creepy feeling...
あっ そういえば…
（ヤサコ）何？
Oh, that's right!
What?
子供を狙ったストーカーが
出るって先生が
Our teacher said a stalker was following kids around lately.
やめてよ 気味悪い
Knock it off! You're scaring me!
あっ ハラケンは？
（ヤサコ）いっけない
Where's Haraken?
Oh no!
Misaki Budist Altar Equipment Store
随分 渋い店に出入りするのね
He sure goes to serious and mature shops.
またしても
訳 分からん行動だわ
His attitude is even more incomprehensible!
（ヤサコ）ねえ ハラケンの
職業上の秘密って何かしら？
So what do you think Haraken's "business secret" is about?
（フミエ）そういえば この間
気になること言ってたわね
Now that you mention it,
I was puzzled about something he said earlier.
“オバちゃんのペットだ”
とかなんとか
Something about his aunt's pet or some such.
（ヤサコ）あっ 言ってたわ
Oh, I remember.
じゃあ そのオバちゃんってのが
サッチーの飼い主ってことね
So his aunt must take care of Satchii.
Random Housewife (42)
なんだかイメージ湧かないわね
That image doesn't suit Satchii.
あっ 見て
Look!
おばさん
The aunt?
Oba-san (aunt) is also used to refer to women who are quite a bit older than the speaker.
しかも メガネ使いね
And she wears glasses, too.
怪しいわ
Suspicious.
あっ フミエちゃん見て！
Look, Fumie!
間違いないわ！
（フミエ）花屋は仮の姿
There's no doubt about it!
The flower shop is just a cover.
あれは
サッチーの本拠地だったんだわ
In reality, it's Satchii's hideout!
それじゃあ
あの人のよさそうなおばさんは…
So that gentle-looking aunt-like lady is...
The enemy of all kids!
（フミエ）
子供の敵 サッチーの首魁(しゅかい)なのよ！
Satchii's boss!
（ヤサコ）結局 ハラケンは
見失っちゃったね
We lost sight of Haraken in the end.
なんとかハラケンの情報を得る
方法はないかな？
I wonder what we can do in order to get some info on him.
そうだ
（フミエ）何？
Oh yeah!
What is it?
メガばあよ
だって会員番号５番よ？
Mega-baa!
He's member Number Five, right?
ハラケンのこと分かるはずよ
She should know a lot about Haraken!
あっ そうか　忘れてた
You're right!
I forgot about that!
（静江(しずえ)）言ったでしょ？
おばあちゃん 温泉旅行で湯河原(ゆがわら)よ
I told you.
She went to the natural hot springs in Yugawara.
忘れてた
I totally forgot.
今すぐ電話しよう
Let's call her right now.
（メガばあ）極楽じゃ
This is paradise.
（トメ）
町内会で こんな温泉に来れるとは
ありがたい ありがたい
I'm so grateful that I can come to this hot spring right here in the middle of town!
まったくじゃ
Indeed!
（トメ）ところで
あんた 誰じゃったかね？
By the way, what's your name again?
（メガばあ）
またトメさん ボケてしもうて
Tome, you're becoming senile. I'm Okonogi, from the dagashi store.
メガシ屋の小此木(おこのぎ)じゃ
（トメ）おお～
そうじゃった そうじゃった
Oh, right, right...
ところで そのメガネ
湯船に持ち込んで大丈夫かえ？
By the way, those glasses...
Is it okay to have them on in the bath?
It's fine, as long as they don't get wet.
お湯を浴びなければ大丈夫じゃ
（トメ）極楽じゃ
This is paradise.
（メガばあ）極楽じゃのう
Indeed, paradise.
（トメ）ところで
あんた 誰じゃったかね？
By the way, who are you again?
（ヤサコ）
あっ よかった　通じたわ
Oh, good! I finally got a hold of you.
おおっ 会員番号８番の
ヤサコではないかえ
Oh, if it isn't Number Eight, Yasako.
どうしたのじゃ？
So what is it?
Well, I wanted to ask you something.
実は聞きたいことがあるのよ
会員番号５番の…
It's about Number Five—
（メガばあ）
ちょ… ちょっと待っとくれ
H-Hang on a sec.
何か言ったかえ？　トメさん
Did you say something, Tome?
そのメガネ
湯船に持ち込んで大丈夫かえ？
I asked if it's okay to put on your glasses while taking the bath.
お湯を浴びなければ大丈夫じゃ
It's fine as long as they don't get wet.
（２人）ぶわっ…
Hello, hello?
切れとる　失礼な孫じゃ
Disconnected.
What a rude granddaughter.
（フミエ）んー…
（ヤサコ）手がかりは途絶えたわ
Our only lead just cut the line.
So we'll have to investigate Satchii on our own, huh?
サッチーでも調べるか
（京子(きょうこ)）交ぜて！
Lemme play with you!
うるさいわね 危険な仕事なの
Pipe down already.
It's a dangerous job!
ケチ！
Meanie!
（フミエ）あっ 片方 サンダル
She only has one sandal!
She's so careless.
ホント そそっかしいんだから
Any more info?
他に情報はないの？
（ヤサコ）なんにも書いてないわ
There's nothing else written here.
こうなったら 私の出番ね
In that case, it's my turn...
Eh?
...to act as the vice president of the Biology Club.
生物部の副部長としてのね
見て
Look.
What's this?
Animal Behavior - Processors and Their Type
（ヤサコ）何これ？
（フミエ）部室にあったのよ
It was in the club room.
Let's investigate Satchii from a biological viewpoint.
生物学的見地から
サッチーを調べるの
（サッチー）
ボク サッチー ヨロシクネ
Me Satchii!
Nice to meet ya!
まあ 黒バグは当然よね
Well, kurobugs are obvious targets.
“黒バグ”と
Kurobugs...
Let's continue.
次 いってみよう
The metabugs are also obvious targets.
メタバグも当然よね
“メタバグ”
Metabugs...
次
Next.
Another obvious target.
当然よね
“メタタグ”
Metatags...
次
Okay, next.
Almost all the items Mega-baa creates are illegal.
メガばあの作ってるものは
あらかた違法なのね
“釣りざお”
Fishing rod...
Well, as expected.
まあ 予想どおりね　次
Next.
ウンチ！
Poop!
Me Satchii!
（サッチー）ボク サッチー
Come with me!
こっち！
（京子）うわっ…
What on earth are you doing?!
何やってんのよ！　危ないでしょ
You know it's dangerous!
（京子）京子もやる！
I wanna play, too!
Densuke...
“デンスケ”
Okay, next is determining its detection range.
さっ 次は距離ね
He can detect it at ten meters.
10メートルで感知
Ten meters...
“10メートル”と
He can detect it at twenty meters.
20メートルで感知
Twenty meters...
“20メートル”と
Look, he can't detect it at thirty meters.
30メートルでは感知しないんだ
Observation is very important, isn't it?
調べてみるものね… んっ？
The Kyuu-chans are expanding the patrol area.
キュウちゃんが
探査範囲を広げてるのね
じゃあ…
Then...
We've learned so many things...
勉強になるわ
Kyoko!
…って 京子！
Poop!
ウンチ！　ヒヒヒヒッ
Run!
逃げて！
Stop!
（ハラケン）待て！
Are you all right?
（ヤサコ）大丈夫？
Don't come any closer!
私たちに近づかないで！
（ハラケン）これ
Here.
That's why I told you it's dangerous!
（ヤサコ）
だから危ないって言ったのに
Don't follow us without permission!
もう勝手についてこないで
I remember when Satchii wasn't here; it was a lot more fun.
サッチーが現れる前は
よかったのに
Hey, Fumie.
ねえ フミエちゃん
ちょっとハラケンにツラすぎない？
Don't you think you're being too hard on Haraken?
A month ago,
１か月前 私のペットが
サッチーに撃ち殺されたの
my pet was shot and killed by Satchii.
It was a mousematon I had raised for three years.
３年も飼ってたネズミのマトン
It only had a small bug...
ちょっとバグがあっただけなのに
問答無用よ
There was no use trying to explain it.
It got killed just for that?
それで あんなに…
I don't want a pet any more
（フミエ）死ぬとツラいから
ペットはもう飼わないわ
because it's painful when they die...
Even if they're not real.
たとえ ウソのペットでもね
Then what about Oyaji?
オヤジは？
（フミエ）だから あれはしもべ
I told you, it's my servant.
It's not a pet to me, but a servant.
ペットじゃなくて しもべ
Okay, Kyoko.
さあ 京子ちゃん
このルートで帰んなさい
Now follow this path to get home.
I didn't know there were so many shrines.
（ヤサコ）
神社 そんなにあったっけ？
The shrines aren't the only places Satchii can't enter.
（フミエ）サッチーが入れないのは
神社だけじゃないわ
Parks, schools, and apparently even hospitals are off-limits.
公園とか学校
病院も入れないみたい
Why can't Satchii enter any of those places?
（ヤサコ）なんで そういう場所に
サッチーは入れないの？
Because of the strict hierarchical organization.
縦割り行政ね
（ヤサコ）えっ？
Huh?
Satchii is from the Ministry of Post,
（フミエ）郵政局のサッチーは
仲の悪いお役所―
so he can't enter areas that fall under other ministries.
School (Ministry of Education)
For example, he can't enter places that belong to the Ministries of Education or Culture.
例えば 文部局とか
文化局の縄張りには入れないのね
Shrine (Ministry of Culture)
The shrines belong to the Ministry of Culture's office.
神社は文化局なのよ
I see.
（ヤサコ）へえー
Also, the inside of a house is called a "home domain",
あと うちの中は
ホームドメインと言って
and it's separate from the "on-road domain", which is found outside.
屋外用のオンロードドメインとは別
That's why it can't enter houses.
だから 絶対 入ってこないわ
Go back home by following the exact route on the map!
（ヤサコ）地図のとおりに帰るのよ
If you don't, that awful Satchii will come after you.
（フミエ）言うとおりにしないと
怖いサッチーが来るよ
Poop...
（京子）ウンチ…
（京子）ふん… ふん…
（ヤサコ）ねえ あの花屋さんが
郵政局の回し者なんて―
It's really hard to believe that lady
やっぱり非現実的よ
is actually an agent of the Ministry of Post.
ヤサコも見たでしょ？
隣からサッチーが出てきたのよ
But you saw it too, right?
Satchii came out of that wall!
（ヤサコ）でも間違ってたら
危ない目に遭うだけ損だわ
But if we're wrong, we'll be in trouble.
（フミエ）よしと
（ヤサコ）ホントに大丈夫？
All set!
Are you sure it's going to be okay?
全部 外したわ
I unequipped everything.
でも なんで
フミエちゃんじゃなくて私なのよ
But why does it have to be me and not you?
私は多すぎて
とても外せないのよ
I have too many items to unequip them all.
ヤサコなら きっと大丈夫だって
Don't worry, you'll be perfectly safe.
メガネ壊されたら弁償よ
Okay, but if my glasses break, you're paying for the repairs!
フン…
大丈夫… よね？
It's gonna work out just fine, right?
（ビームの発射音）
（ヤサコ）ああっ ダメじゃん！
It's not working!
（ヤサコ）ダメじゃーん！
あの子 さっきの…
Isn't that...
the girl from before?
おっかしいな
スキャンではバグがないんだけどな
That's odd.
The scan didn't report that you had any bugs!
しっかりしてよ お年玉２年分よ
Come on!
That was almost two years' otoshidama!
変だな… ねえ ヤサコ
How weird...
Yasako, you weren't infected by some bad bug, now were you?
なんか悪いバグでも
もらってんじゃないの？
失礼ね
How rude!
あっ ところでさ フミエちゃん
ふと思ったんだけど…
Hey, Fumie...
It just came to me.
何よ
What?
メガネの電源 切って
行けばいいんじゃないの？
Can't we just turn off our glasses?
メガネの電源 切ったのなんか
１年ぶりだわ
It's been a year since I last turned off my glasses.
なんかメガネがないと不安
I feel uneasy without them.
（フミエ）携帯も兼ねてるし
めったなことじゃ切れないのよね
The cell phone's embedded,
so I rarely cut power to my glasses.
（ヤサコ）私たち
もう普通の子供に戻れないのかしら
Maybe it's too late for us to become normal kids again.
（店員）あら いらっしゃい
Oh, welcome!
（フミエ）あっ あの…
（店員）はい
U-U-Um...
Yes?
おば… おばさんは…
（店員）はい？
A-Are you...
Yes?
郵政局の回し者ですか？
Are you an agent of the Ministry of Post?!
おばさんは
原川(はらかわ)君のおばさんですか？
What she means is,
are you Harakawa's aunt?
原川君？
Harakawa?
あっ あなたたち
ケンちゃんのお友達ね
Oh, so you must be Ken's friends.
（ヤサコ）はい
Yes.
親戚ってこと？　違うわよ
So you want to know if we're relatives?
Not at all.
ケンちゃんのことは
小さい頃から知ってるけど
But I've know him since he was a child.
ぶはっ… 原川君が
オバちゃんって呼んでる人は
Are you the lady that Harakawa calls "aunt"?!
おばさんですか？
（店員）ケンちゃんには
花屋さんって呼ばれてるわ
Ken always calls me "Flower Lady".
変なこと聞くのね
You sure ask strange things.
（フミエ）そうですか
（ヤサコ）どうも失礼しました
So you aren't...
We're sorry for bothering you.
あっ ねえ
Listen...
あの子 事故からこっち
あんまり笑わなくなっちゃって
Ken stopped smiling after the accident.
ケンちゃんと仲良くしてあげてね
Please be cheerful around him.
（フミエ）
やっぱり ここだったのね
So you were here.
去年 自由研究の途中で
カンナとケンカしちゃったんだ
Last year, during the middle of our research,
I had a fight with Kanna.
僕が真面目にやらなかったから
カンナが怒って
Kanna was upset because
I wasn't taking it seriously.
この交差点に行くって
１人で出かけて
So she ran off by herself, saying she would come to this crossroad.
そのまま帰ってこなかったんだ
She never came back.
ハラケン
Haraken...
カンナはイリーガルに
殺されたかもしれないんだ
Kanna was probably killed by an Illegal.
（ハラケン）今の交通システムが
You know that the modern traffic system
電脳空間を使っているのは
知っているよね？
is plugged into cyberspace, right?
（フミエ）
ああ 電脳ナビってやつよね
Yeah, the cybernavi.
カンナをはねたのも
It appears that the car
電脳ナビで
自動運転中の車だったらしいんだ
that killed Kanna was autopiloted by a cybernavi.
（フミエ）なんですって？
What?!
（ヤサコ）でも自動運転は 絶対に
事故が起きないはずなんじゃ…
But isn't the autopilot supposed to be 100% safe?
（ハラケン）オバちゃんが言ってた
My aunt said
“電脳ナビの誤作動の原因は
イリーガルかもしれない”って
that the cause of the cybernavi's malfunction
might've been an Illegal.
（フミエ）それでイリーガルを…
So that's why you research Illegals...
（ヤサコ）
そのオバちゃんって誰なの？
Who's this aunt of yours?
それも守秘義務？
Is it also a duty of confidentiality?
お父さんの妹だからオバちゃん
She's my father's younger sister,
so she's my aunt.
今 大黒市の空間管理の
仕事やってるんだ
She's currently employed at the Daikoku Cyberspace Management department.
（ヤサコ）そうなの
Oh really?
（ハラケン）
サッチーを導入したのは
オバちゃんなんだ
It's my aunt who installed Satchii.
僕が今年もイリーガルの
研究をしたいって言ったら
When I told her that I wanted to continue my research on Illegals this year,
１分だけ止められるように
してくれたんだ
she enabled me to stop Satchii for exactly one minute.
もっとも 僕の出せる命令は
But the only commands I can use
待てと お座りと
お手だけだけどね
are "stop," "sit," and "shake hands".
そうなんだ
Is that so...
（ハラケン）イリーガルなんて
存在自体 知られてないし
The existence of Illegals is not recognized as such,
自動運転中に起きた事故は
運転手の過失にはならないから
and so the autopilot car incident
is not considered a driver error.
事故は 結局―
So in the end, the case was closed,
カンナの不注意が原因ってことで
終わっちゃった
and it was stated that Kanna's negligence was the cause.
僕は今年も自由研究をやる
I'll continue with our research this year, too.
今年は僕がやらなきゃダメなんだ
I'm the only one who can do it now.
でないと
カンナが浮かばれないんだ
Otherwise,
Kanna won't rest in peace.
ハラケン
悪の手先なんて言ってごめんね
Haraken...
I'm sorry for calling you a pawn of evil.
研究 私も手伝うわ
I'll help you with the research.
私も　同じクラブじゃない
Me too!
We're in the same club after all!
ありがとう
Thank you.
あっ お母さん？
Oh, mom?
京子が？
１時間も前に送り返したわよ
Kyoko?
But I sent her home over an hour ago.
（フミエ）
京子ちゃん どうかしたの？
Something happened to Kyoko?
（ヤサコ）まだ帰ってないって
She's not home yet.
やっぱり連れて帰るべきだったわ
I knew it! We should have taken her home.
京子ちゃんって
今日 連れていた？
Kyoko... you mean, the little girl who was with you earlier?
そうよ
That's right.
それ さっき見たよ
中津交差点のほうで
I saw her a little while ago.
Near Nakatsu Crossroads.
（ハラケン）いた？
（ヤサコ）ううん
Did you find her?
No...
（ヤサコ）そっちは？
（ハラケン）いない
And you?
Me neither.
（ヤサコ）
なんで地図が使えないの？
電話もつながらないわ
Why can't we use the map?
Her phone is out of reach, too!
The signal is weak in this area.
この辺 電波状態が悪いんだ
大黒市で２番目に悪いわ
It's the second worst place in Daikoku.
ねえ 路地の中は？
What about the alleyways?
この辺り すごく入り組んでるし
The streets zigzag a lot here.
手分けして捜しましょう
Then let's split up and search for her!
京子ちゃん！
Kyoko!
（ヤサコ）京子！
どうしよう… 私 姉失格だわ
What should I do?
I'm a failure as an older sister...
サッチー
Satchii...
デンスケも危ない
早く捜さなきゃ！
Densuke's in danger, too!
I have to find her quickly!
あっ 京子！
Kyoko!
（京子）わあっ…
京子！
Kyoko!
京子 大丈夫？
Kyoko, are you all right?
（女性）ハァー
この子たち あんたの知り合い？
Do you know these two?
あっ はい　妹です
Yes, she's my little sister.
この辺は子供には危ないから
気をつけて
This area is very dangerous. Be careful.
前にも事故があったのよ
There's even been an accident before.
ああ… 知ってます
Yes... I know.
あの… ありがとうございました
Um, thank you very much.
ヤサコ！
Yasako!
あっ 京子ちゃん よかった
Kyoko!
I'm so glad to see you!
あっ！　ストーカー
Ah, it's the stalker!
サッチー！
It's Satchii!
（女性）待て
Stop!
Stop
お手
Shake hands.
お座り
Sit.
（ヤサコ）あ… あなたは？
Who are you?
君たち 随分と危ないオモチャ
ぶら下げてるみたいね
You guys are playing with dangerous toys.
な… なんのことですか？
I-I don't know what you're talking about.
（女性）
私はね ハッキングにも詳しいのよ
You know...
I'm well-versed in hacking.
メタタグとかね
Like metatags and such.
So who are you?
（フミエ）あなた 一体 何者？
（ハラケン）
見つかったんだ？　よかった
You've finally found her!
Thank goodness.
ケンちゃん
Ken!
あっ オバちゃん
A-Aunt!
（２人）オ… オバちゃん？
A-Aunt?!
（オバちゃん）
んもう～ ケンちゃんったら
C'mon, Ken...
そのオバちゃんってのは
やめろよ～
I've told you not to call me "aunt".
私 まだ17歳の
ピチピチギャルなんだから
I'm a lively 17-year old gal, after all!
ピ… ピチピチギャル？
L-Lively gal?!
死語？
An outdated word?
紹介するよ ヤサコとフミエ
I'll introduce you.
Yasako, Fumie.
この人は僕のオバちゃん
My aunt.
ケンちゃん 悪い友達とは
遊ぶなって言ったでしょ？
Ken!
I've told you not to hang around with bad company, haven't I?
悪くないって
They're not bad!
僕と一緒に
自由研究やってくれるんだ
They're helping me with my ongoing research.
まあ いいわ
Well, whatever.
今日は見逃してあげるから
さっさと行きなさい
I'll turn a blind eye this time, so get lost.
さっ ケンちゃん帰ろう
Okay, Ken. Let's go home.
お父さん まだ出ないでよ
Dad, don't come out yet!
（一郎(いちろう)）分かってる 分かってる
I know, I know.
今日は いろいろあってクタクタよ
全然 先が読めないわ
I'm so tired after what happened today.
I can't figure out what will happen next.
（一郎）お父さんも
いろいろあってクタクタだよ
I'm tired from work, too.
（ヤサコ）お父さんのクタクタとは
訳が違うの！
Your tiredness has nothing to do with my tiredness!
（一郎）なんだよ 冷たいな
Why are you suddenly being so cold to me?
（ヤサコ）子供をいじめる
悪い大人がいなくなりますように…
I pray that all adults who are mean to kids disappear.
お父さんはな
若い女の子の気持ちはさっぱりだよ
I don't understand a woman's feelings at all.
Daikoku Municipal Office
（一郎）
なんで こんなに必要なんだ？
Why do you need so much?
Director of the Cyberspace Management Department
税金を使うんだから
ちゃんとした説明をしてくれ
If I'm going to employ this much of the taxpayers' money on it,
then you at least owe me an explanation.
If I say it's necessary, it's necessary.
必要だから必要だと言ってるんです
Special Advisor Tamako Harakawa
私は空間管理室 顧問で
権限もあるんです
As a consultant of cyberspace management, I have the authority to do so!
（一郎）
顧問と言っても客員じゃないか
Even if you're a consultant, you're still a simple employee.
室長こそ
金沢市(かなざわし)からの出向でしょ？
As for you, Director, you've only recently transferred from Kanazawa, correct?
追加の申請やっといてくださいね
Don't forget about the additional request.
まったく…
若い女の子の気持ちはさっぱりだよ
I don't understand a woman's feelings at all.
Have you finished the adjustments?
どう？　調整 終わった？
（技師）はい
Yes, ma'am.
でも こんな強力なマトンが
本当に必要なんですか？
But do we really need such a powerful automaton?
これでも足りないくらいよ
We need it so badly that even this won't be enough.
You'll understand later.
そのうち イヤでも分かるわ
We had such a hard time yesterday!
（フミエ）
昨日はヒドい目に遭ったよね
Yeah...
そうね
So you just moved to this town?
（ハラケン）
引っ越したばかりなんだね
Right.
そうね
Okay, let's decide how we're going to split the research workload.
（フミエ）
さあ 研究の分担を決めましょう
そうね
Yeah.
What's wrong with you, Yasako?
どうしたの？　ヤサコ
なんか脱力してるけど
I know you must be tired, but...
昨日のヒドい目がこたえたの？
Is it because of all the bad stuff that happened yesterday?
It's not just that...
ヒドい目は
昨日だけじゃないのよ
何それ？
Then what is it?
（京子）ブンブ～ン！
ブンブ～ン！
She's been like that since this morning.
（ヤサコ）今朝から ずっとあれよ
Like that...
あれって もしかして…
You mean...!
I guess she's started to admire Haraken's aunt.
ハラケンのオバちゃんに
すっかり憧れちゃったみたい
It's her new thing.
新しいマイブームよ
ブ～ン ブ～ン！
Preview
Next time on Dennou Coil:
Move out! Coil Investigation Agency.
Move Out!
Coil Investigation Agency
See you next time!
（ヤサコ）
次回 「電脳コイル」
〝出動!!
コイル探偵局 〞
お楽しみに